British Labour History Ephemera on Microfilm 5573 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
British Labour History Ephemera on Microfilm
1800-1900
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Labour Party (Great Britain)
5573 mf
5.11 cubic feet
46 microfilm reels
Records (documents), ephemera, microfilm.
Leaflets, periodical articles, pamphlets, speeches, lectures, minutes, annuals, conference reports covering topics in British labor history including strikes, trade-unions, the eight-hour movement, women and work, and socialism.
3337593
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 20, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 05, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Labour Party grew out of the trade union movement of the late 19th century, and surpassed the Liberal Party as the main opposition to the Conservatives in the early 1920s. While beginning as a working class movement, it today is largely middle class. In the 1930s and 1940s it stressed national planning, using nationalization of industry as a tool, but it never favoured worker control of industry. Labour has had several spells in government, first as minority governments under Ramsay MacDonald in 1924 and 192931. MacDonald and half his cabinet split with the mainstream of the Party and were denounced as traitors. Labour was a junior partner in the wartime coalition from 19401945. After the famous 1945 landslide under Clement Attlee (194551) it set up the welfare state with the National Health Service, nationalised a fifth of the economy, joined NATO and opposed the Soviet Union in the Cold War. Under Harold Wilson in 196470 it promoted economic modernisation. Labour was in government again in 197479, under Wilson and then James Callaghan. Escalating economic crises (the "Winter of Discontent") and battles with labour unions, together with an unpopular anti-nuclear foreign policy, doomed it to Opposition status during the Thatcher years, 1979-1997.
Labour returned with a landslide 179 seat majority in the 1997 general election under the leadership of Tony Blair. The party's large majority in the House of Commons was slightly reduced to 167 in the 2001 general election and more substantially reduced to 66 in 2005. Under Gordon Brown it was defeated in the 2010 general election and now forms the Opposition to a Conservative/Liberal-Democrat coalition.
Scope and Contents
Included in this collection are leaflets, periodical articles, pamphlets, speeches, lectures, minutes, annuals, conference reports covering topics in British labor history including strikes, trade-unions, the eight-hour movement, women and work, and socialism.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5214 mf: British Labor History Pamphlets on Microfilm
Eight-hour movement.; Labor -- Great Britain.; Labor movement -- Great Britain.; Socialism -- Great Britain.; Working class -- Great Britain.; Strikes and lockouts -- Great Britain.; Labor unions -- Great Britain.; Women -- Employment -- Great Britain.; Labour Party (Great Britain)
3337593
- Items 1-37, 1886-1898; Microfilm (Reel 1)
  - Item 1: An Address on Socialism, Publication (Reel 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By Thomas Barclay. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Mass of Christ, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Francis Adams. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Individualism and Socialism, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Grant Allen. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Contribution Card, Publication (Reel 1)
    Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Admission Card, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 6: Election of Representatives to the Trades Council (Ms. Letter), Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 7: Among the Suffolk Labourers with the 'Red Van', Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 8: An Address to the Army, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 9: An Anarchist Address to Workingmen, Publication (Reel 1)
    Leaflet. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Recreation in Ancoats, Publication (Reel 1)
    By A.B. Wakeield. Lecture. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Sweating: Two Reports, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Anon. article. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: 50 Years' Cotton Trade, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Samuel Andrew. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: The Cottagers' Allotment Gardens Bill, Publication (Reel 1)
    By J. Arch. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Charles Darwin and Karl Marx, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Edward Aveling. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: The Eight Hours' Working-Day, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 16: Wilhelm Liebknecht and the Social-Democratic Movement in Germany, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Aveling Edward. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Shelley's Socialism, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Edward and Eleanor Aveling. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: The Coal Strike of 1893, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Emerson Bainbridge. Item is in English.
  - Item 19: Distress in East London, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Barnett, Samuel A. Item is in English.
  - Item 20: Socialism and Soldiering, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Bateman, George. Item is in English.
  - Item 21: A Short History of the Paris Commune, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Bax, E. Belfort. Item is in English.
  - Item 22: Looking Backward, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Bellamy, Edward. Item is in English.
  - Item 23: Objections to Socialism Answered, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Bicker-Caarten, D. Item is in English.
  - Item 24: Why Working Men Should be Liberals, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Binney, F.A. Item is in English.
  - Item 25: Women and Work, II, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Black, Clementine. Item is in English.
  - Item 26: A Working Woman's Speech, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 27: Altruism, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Blatchford, Robert. Item is in English.
  - Item 28: Competition: A Plain Lesson for the Workers, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 29: Land Nationalism, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 30: Merrie England, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 31: The New Religion, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 32: The Pope's Socialism, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 33: Real Socialism, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 34: Socialism: A Reply to the Encyclical of the Pope, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 35: Some Tory Socialisms, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 36: Three Open Letters to the Bishop of Manchester on Socialism, Publication (Reel 1)
  - Item 37: The Doom of the Cotton Trade, Publication (Reel 1)
    By Bonami. Item is in English.
- Items 38-39, 1889-1891; Microfilm (Reel 2)
  - Item 1: Labour and Life of the People Vol. 1, East London, Publication (Reel 2)
    By Booth, Charles. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Labour and Life of the People, Vol. 2, London, Publication (Reel 2)
- Items 40-42, 1892-1899; Microfilm (Reel 3)
  - Item 1: The Aged Poor in England and Wales - Condition, Publication (Reel 3)
  - Item 2: Old Age Pensions and the Aged Poor - A Proposal, Publication (Reel 3)
  - Item 3: Pauperism, a Picture and the Endowment of Old Age - An Argument, Publication (Reel 3)
- Items 43-72, 1880-1899; Microfilm (Reel 4)
  - Item 1: Labour Disputes and the Chamber of Commerce, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Boulton, S.B. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: State-Directed Emigration: its Necessity, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 3: The Eight Hours' Movement, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Bradlaugh, Charles. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Sidelights on Poor Law Administration, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Brooke, Albert. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Labour's Death RollL The Tragedy of Toil, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Burns, John. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Music and Musicians, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Burns, John. Speech. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: The Trail of the Financial Serpent, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 8: Working Men and the Political Situation, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Burt, Thomas. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Civilisation: its Cause and Cure, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Carpenter, Edward. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: England Arise: Socialist Marching Song, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 11: England's Ideal: a Tract, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 12: Co-operative Production, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 13: Political Economy of Socialism, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Carruthers, John. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Socialism and Radicalism, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 15: The Crushing Defeat of Trade Unionism in Australia, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Champion, H.H. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: An Eight-Hour Law, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 17: The Facts about the Unemployed, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 18: The Federation of Labour, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 19: The Labour Movement: A Multitude of Counsellors, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 20: The Labour Platform at the Next Election, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 21: The New Labour Party, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 22: The Chief Cause of our Want of Employment, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 23: A Series of Speeches in the House of Commons, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Burns, John. Session 1900. Item is in English.
  - Item 24: Effect of the Factory System in General, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Clarke, Allen. Item is in English.
  - Item 25: Effects of the Factory System on Health, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 26: Effects of the Factory System on Women and Children, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 27: "Voices" and Other Verse, Publication (Reel 4)
  - Item 28: What do we Live for?, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Clarke, Allen. see item no. 377 (reel 42). Item is in English.
  - Item 29: Commonwealth: A Socialist Magazine Vol. 1, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Canon Henry Scott (Editor). Item is in English.
  - Item 30: A Song of Freedom, Publication (Reel 4)
    By Burrows, Herbert. Item is in English.
- Items 73-78, 1883-1896; Microfilm (Reel 5)
  - Item 1: Socialism and Survival of the Fittest, Publication (Reel 5)
    By Connell, J. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: St. John: The Cry of the Children, Publication (Reel 5)
    By Conway, Katherine. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: St. John: The Road to Socialism, Publication (Reel 5)
  - Item 4: Co-operative Wholesale Society's Annual, Publication (Reel 5)
    1st Volume. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Guarantees Against Unlawful War, Publication (Reel 5)
    By Copland, Elijah. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Lecture on Agriculture, Publication (Reel 5)
    By Cottn, Sir A. Item is in English.
- Items 79-91, 1880-1900; Microfilm (Reel 6)
  - Item 1: Retrospective Lessons on Railway Strikes, Publication (Reel 6)
    By Croker, E. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Eight Hours Question, Publication (Reel 6)
    By Cox, Harold. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Housing the Poor, Publication (Reel 6)
    By Cross, Richard A. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Homes of the Poor in London, Publication (Reel 6)
  - Item 5: Condition of the Industrial Classes of Bradford and District, Publication (Reel 6)
    By Cudworth, W. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Anarchist Socialism versus State Socialism, Publication (Reel 6)
    By Davidson, J. Morrison. pamphlet. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Is the G.O.M. a Liberal?, Publication (Reel 6)
    By Davidson, J. Morrison. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: The New Book of Kings, Publication (Reel 6)
  - Item 9: Labour and Labour Laws, Publication (Reel 6)
    By Davis, J.E. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Reports of the Trade Union Congress Taken from History and Recollections of the T.U.C., Publication (Reel 6)
    By Davis, W.J. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Christian Socialism, Publication (Reel 6)
    By Dearmer, Rev. Percy. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Labour Electoral v. Independent Labour, Publication (Reel 6)
    leaflet. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: What Means This Strike?, Publication (Reel 6)
    By DeLeon, Daniel. Item is in English.
- Items 92-105, 1887-1895; Microfilm (Reel 7)
  - Item 1: William Saunders, Publication (Reel 7)
    By Democrat, Ed. Periodical. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Common Misconceptions About Socialism, Publication (Reel 7)
    By Derfel, R.J. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: The Genesis of Capital, Publication (Reel 7)
    By Deville, Gabriel. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: The Good Time Coming, Publication (Reel 7)
    By Diack, W. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Socialism and Current Politics, Publication (Reel 7)
  - Item 6: The Steamy Side of Trades Unionis, for Women, Publication (Reel 7)
    By Dilke, Emilia F.S. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Trades Unionism for Women, Publication (Reel 7)
  - Item 8: "For the Kingdom of God is Here", Publication (Reel 7)
    By Drysdale, Chas. D. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: The Case for the Fourth Clause, Publication (Reel 7)
    By Elihu (Samuel Washington). Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Milk and Postage Stamps, Publication (Reel 7)
    By Elihu. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: A Nation of Slaves, Publication (Reel 7)
  - Item 12: Simple Division, Publication (Reel 7)
  - Item 13: Whose Dog Art Thou?, Publication (Reel 7)
  - Item 14: Economic Review Vol. 1 (Periodical), Publication (Reel 7)
- Items 106-114, 1888-1898; Microfilm (Reel 8)
  - Item 1: Engineering: A Few Extracts from the Press on the Present Dispute in the Engineering Trade, Publication (Reel 8)
  - Item 2: Engineering: List of Federated Firms who Resisted the Demand for a 48 Hours' Working Week, Publication (Reel 8)
  - Item 3: Engineering Trades Lock-Out: Mass Meeting - Hull Trades and Labour Council, Publication (Reel 8)
  - Item 4: Engineers' Federation Lock-Out: Meetings - York Trades and Labour Council, Publication (Reel 8)
  - Item 5: Fabian Society Report, Publication (Reel 8)
    Tracts 1-104 non on this microfilm, but available on application. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: The Principles of Socialism Made Plain, Publication (Reel 8)
    By Fairman, Frank. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: The Featherstone Massacre, Publication (Reel 8)
  - Item 8: The Real History of Money Island, Publication (Reel 8)
    By Flurscheim, Michael. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: The Legal Eight Hour Question, Publication (Reel 8)
    By Foote, G.W. and G.B. Shaw. Item is in English.
- Items 115-117, 1882-1905; Microfilm (Reel 9)
  - Item 1: Forecasts of the Coming Century by a Decade of Writers, Publication (Reel 9)
  - Item 2: The Socialism of Jesus, Publication (Reel 9)
    By Gass, M. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: General Alliance of Operative House and Ship Painters: Quarterly and Annual Reports, Publication (Reel 9)
- Item 118, 1878-1881; Microfilm (Reel 10)
  - Item 1: General Alliance of Operative House and Ship Painters, Quarterly Reports: Minutes of Annual Meetings, Publication (Reel 10)
- Items 119-148, 1882-1898; Microfilm (Reel 11)
  - Item 1: The Crime of Poverty, an address, Publication (Reel 11)
    By George, Henry. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Land and People, Publication (Reel 11)
  - Item 3: Moses: An Address, Publication (Reel 11)
  - Item 4: "Thou Shalt Not Steal", Publication (Reel 11)
  - Item 5: The Progress of the Working Classes in the Last Half Century, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Griffen, Robert. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Society Classified, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Girlestone, E.D. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: On Strikes, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Glasier, J.B. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: The Government Organization of Unemployed Labour, Publication (Reel 11)
  - Item 9: The History of the Poor Law, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Green, Gertrude. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Grimsby Sunday Association, Publication (Reel 11)
  - Item 11: Collectivism, a speech translated by Alex M. Thompson, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Guesde, Jules. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: The Miners of Scotland, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Haddow, Robert. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: The Old and New Unionism, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Hall, Leonard. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Socialism, Tariffism and "Free" Trade: A Reply to the Clarion, Publication (Reel 11)
  - Item 15: The Necessity of an Independent Labor Party, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Hammill, Fred. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: Railway Labour, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Harkness, Margaret E. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: The New Trades-Unionism, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Harrison, Frederic. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: Constitutional Socialism, without Confiscation and without Revolution, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Hart, C. Item is in English.
  - Item 19: The Secular Work of Jesus Christ: His Apostles and the Church of England, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Headlam, Rev. Stewart D. Item is in English.
  - Item 20: Women and the Glove Trade, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Heather-Bigg, Ada. Item is in English.
  - Item 21: Jesus the Socialist: a Lecture Delivered in 1896, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Hird, Dennis. Item is in English.
  - Item 22: Doehm-Bawer's Criticism of Marx, translated by Eden and Cedar Paul, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Hilferding, Rudolf. Item is in English.
  - Item 23: Social Democracy, or Democratic Socialism, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Hobart, H.W. Item is in English.
  - Item 24: The Financial Condition of Trades Unions, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Howell, George. Item is in English.
  - Item 25: The Provident Side of Trades Unionism, Publication (Reel 11)
  - Item 26: Hull Labor Church, Publication (Reel 11)
  - Item 27: The Approaching Catastrophe in India, Publication (Reel 11)
    By Hyndman, H.M. Item is in English.
  - Item 28: Bleeding to Death, Publication (Reel 11)
  - Item 29: TheChicago Riots and the Class War in the USA, Publication (Reel 11)
  - Item 30: Commercial Crises of the Nineteenth Century, Publication (Reel 11)
- Items 149-153, 1881-1896; Microfilm (Reel 12)
  - Item 1: The Dawn of a Revolutionary Epoch, Publication (Reel 12)
  - Item 2: The Economics of Socialism, Publication (Reel 12)
  - Item 3: Eight Hours the Maximum Working Day, Publication (Reel 12)
  - Item 4: England for All, Publication (Reel 12)
  - Item 5: Historical Basis of Socialism in England, Publication (Reel 12)
- Items 154-163, 1884-1900; Microfilm (Reel 13)
  - Item 1: How I Became a Socialist, Publication (Reel 13)
  - Item 2: Mr. Gladstone and the Eight Hours Law, Publication (Reel 13)
  - Item 3: The Radicals and Socialism, Publication (Reel 13)
  - Item 4: The Single Tax versus Social Democracy, Publication (Reel 13)
  - Item 5: Socialism and Rent-Appropriation: A Dialogue, Publication (Reel 13)
    By Hyndman, H.M. with Engry George. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Socialism and Slavery, Publication (Reel 13)
  - Item 7: Something Better than Emigration, Publication (Reel 13)
  - Item 8: A Summary of the Principles of Socialism, Publication (Reel 13)
    By Hyndman, H.M. and William Morris. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Will Socialism Benefit the English People, Publication (Reel 13)
    By Hyndman, H.M. and Charles Bardlaugh. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Independent Labour Party Reports: 1893, 1894, 1895, 1896, 1897, 1898, 1899, 1900, Publication (Reel 13)
- Items 164-170, 1885-1903; Microfilm (Reel 14)
  - Item 1: ILP News, Publication (Reel 14)
  - Item 2: Humanity's Debt to Thomas Paine, Publication (Reel 14)
    By Ingersoll, Robert G. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: International Arbitration and Peace Association: Report 5th Annual Meeting, Publication (Reel 14)
  - Item 4: International Working Men's Congress, Publication (Reel 14)
  - Item 5: The Relations Between Employers and Workmen in Engineering Works, Publication (Reel 14)
    By Iorns, C.R. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: The Agricultural Labourer, Publication (Reel 14)
    By J (G.R.). Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Reporter and Socialist: An Interview Explaining the Aims and Objects of Socialism, Publication (Reel 14)
    By Jonas, Alexander. Item is in English.
- Items 171-175, 1880-1885; Microfilm (Reel 15)
  - Item 1: Co-operation in Danger!, Publication (Reel 15)
    By Jones, Lloyd. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Socialist Catechism, Publication (Reel 15)
    By Jones, J.L. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Socialist Rhymes, Publication (Reel 15)
    By Joynes, J.L. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: The Socialist Catechism, Publication (Reel 15)
  - Item 5: Justice, Publication (Reel 15)
- Items 176-190, 1883-1898; Microfilm (Reel 16)
  - Item 1: Socialism and Christianity, Publication (Reel 16)
    By Kaufman, Rev. M. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Socialism and Communism, Publication (Reel 16)
  - Item 3: The Socialist Commonwealth, Publication (Reel 16)
    By Kautsky, Karl. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: The Nationalization of our Railway System, Publication (Reel 16)
    By Keddell, F. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Good and Bad Federation, Publication (Reel 16)
    By King, P.J. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Fruits of Philosophy: An Essay on the Population Question, Publication (Reel 16)
    By Kowlton, Chas. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Agriculture, Publication (Reel 16)
    By Kropotkin, Peter. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: An Appeal to the Young, Publication (Reel 16)
  - Item 9: Anarchism: Its Philosophy and Ideal, Publication (Reel 16)
  - Item 10: Anarchist Communism: Its Basis and Principles, Publication (Reel 16)
    By Kropotkinm, Peter. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: The Commune of Paris, Publication (Reel 16)
  - Item 12: Law and Authority, An Anarchist Essay, Publication (Reel 16)
  - Item 13: The Place of Anarchism in Socialist Evolution, Publication (Reel 16)
  - Item 14: The State: Its Historical Role, Publication (Reel 16)
  - Item 15: The Wage System (Freedom Pamphlet No. 1), Publication (Reel 16)
- Items 191-192, 1895-1900; Microfilm (Reel 17)
  - Item 1: War!, Publication (Reel 17)
  - Item 2: Labour Annual: 1895, 1896, 1898, 1899, 1900, Publication (Reel 17)
- Items 193-198, 1886-1893; Microfilm (Reel 18)
  - Item 1: Hymn and Tune Book, Publication (Reel 18)
    By The Labour Church. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Labor Day: A Monster Demostration, Publication (Reel 18)
  - Item 3: Labor Emancipation League, Publication (Reel 18)
  - Item 4: Labor Leader, Publication (Reel 18)
  - Item 5: Labor Prophet: The Organ of the Labor Church, Publication (Reel 18)
    By Trevor, John (editor). No. 1 Jan 1892 - No. 13 Jan 1893. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Labor Tribune: The Organ of the Miners, Ironworkers, Nut & Bolt Forgers of Great Britain, Publication (Reel 18)
- Items 199-200, 1885-1893; Microfilm (Reel 19)
  - Item 1: The Right to Leisure, Publication (Reel 19)
    By LaFargue, Paul. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Lancashire Little Bee: Political Buzzings, Publication (Reel 19)
- Items 201-213, 1888-1897; Microfilm (Reel 20)
  - Item 1: Land and Labor: the Dragon of the Land Nationalization Society, Publication (Reel 20)
  - Item 2: Land Nationalization Society Tract XXXV: Opinions of Leading Thinkers, Publication (Reel 20)
  - Item 3: Principles of the English Poor Law, Publication (Reel 20)
    By Lansbury, George. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Political Parties and Working Men's Rights, Publication (Reel 20)
    By Leadman, I.S. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: The Commune of Paris: Its Story and Meaning, Publication (Reel 20)
    By Leatham, James. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Was Jesus a Socialist?, Publication (Reel 20)
  - Item 7: Syllabus of Lectures, Publication (Reel 20)
    By Leeds Central ILP Club. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Two Addresses, Publication (Reel 20)
    By Leeds Labor Church. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Mass Meeting, Publication (Reel 20)